hi so what we're going to actually cover first is really really important we're
going to cover the differences between retail traders and professional traders
but we're going to start at professional traders 101 which is essentially
defining what a professional trader actually is and what a successful
professional trader actually does now this is really important and you should
not underestimate it simply because from a professional traders perspective I can
tell you uncategorically that retail traders totally misinterpret and
misunderstand what professional traders do now this leads to a big problem
because essentially retail traders their objectives are really to emulate what
successful traders do but do it with their own money now it's a problem because
it leads to retail traders to make many many many mistakes and go down the wrong
path of trading now once you understand what a professional trader actually is
and what a successful professional trader does then you can begin to emulate with
your own money what a professional trader does so we're going to go over to the
stage now and I want you to really focus on your objectives here your objective
as a retail trader is to make money using your own money and
in the process to emulate successful professional traders therefore we're going to
start by defining exactly what a professional trader is then we'll move on in the next
section to what successful professional traders do let's go over to the stage and I'll see you on the other side
so the first part we're going to do is actually define what professional traders do
question one what does a guy at investment bank do a professional trader what does a guy at a hedge fund do they're
they're quite different functions quite different roles what does it mean for the
retail trader who's trying to emulate them and the differences between professional traders and retail traders
so professional traders at investment banks
90% of a traders time at an investment bank is actually spent being a market maker and only 10% of their time is actually spent
trading the bank's money I'm using that money in an attempt to make a profit
so when you look on CNBC Bloomberg on the television and you see the trip that you see the trading floors with all the guys
walking around and lots of screens at their desks at their desks what are they actually doing well 90% of the time they're just making prices in the market to clients
so is that what we do as retail traders
who says yes
it's clearly not we don't have any clients we don't care
the objective here like this gentleman
already outlined
is to just make money using our own money to make money
got no interest in market making
but let's have a look at the business how it actually works
the market making business is literally the bread and butter of the bank
and it's split into two categories really
it's the it's an agency business and a risk business
okay what do we mean by an agency business you're not on risk to the client
so the agency business literally
a guy calls in from a pension fund or a hedge fund and they want to buy an asset
they give the bank the order to buy the asset on their behalf
and it's just executed in the market
and a commission is charged
and commissions are charged in basis points
and 100 basis points is 1%
so what's a typical commission these days
anybody what do you think
on an agency trade
who said five basis points
yeah four or five basis points
over around a decade ago
the industry standard was about 20-25
for agency business
so all things being constant in terms of volume in the markets
the agency business is down 80% in the last decade
that's one of the reasons why banks struggle
and this is totally risk-free stuff to the bank
the phone just rings
a salesperson takes the order
puts it in the system
and it goes through
typically into an algorithm
and the algorithm executes it electronically
so there's very little human intervention
and that's pretty much 80% of all market-making business
so what does that tell you
in terms of the time split of a trader
at an investment bank
what does it tell you
what was the number in terms of time
they were spending 90% market-making year
and 80% of its agency
so the vast majority of the time
they're actually just sitting at computers
watching orders being executed in the market
and just supervising them
that's the vast majority of what
professional traders at investment banks do
it's pretty boring
but the perception is that
it's totally the opposite
people think that trading floors
are these huge hives of activity
with lots of noise
and everyone shouting at each other
it's just completely the opposite now
that you can walk onto the Goldman Sachs
Morgan Stanley
Bank of America Merrill Lynch trading floor
and it's quieter than this room
that's what they're doing most of the time
so two things
is firstly get it out your head
that a trader's job is exciting
it's not
it's literally the opposite
it's really really boring
and secondly if you're a retail trader
the vast majority of what guys
at investment banks do
if you're trying to emulate them
you're not emulating
what they do the vast majority of the time
because your objective is to make money
using your own money
not execute client's orders
through an algorithm
but 20% of the market making business
is on risk
so instead of a client calling into the office
pension fund, hedge fund
and giving a risk free order
to the trader
which they just bung in an algorithm
the phone rings
and a sales person picks it up
and the client asks
for a price
in the asset
and the market maker goes on risk
to the client
what does that mean?
they take the other side
so an example here
buying $10 million of Apple stock
at $500
so 20,000 shares
what actually happens
the trader is short
on the other side
so they're short
$10 million of Apple stock
at $500
if they buy it back above $500
they lose
so what does that actually mean?
well it means
the trading function
in the risk model
is to be the gatekeeper
of the bank's balance sheet
so the trader uses
the bank's balance sheet
to attract business
into the company
so if they lose a dollar
on that
they buy it back at $501
they're losing $20,000
does that make sense?
now if they're trading
they're not trading
one stock at a time
typically
a professional trader
in an investment bank
will be trading
between 50 and 100 stocks
at any one time
and what that is known as
in the industry
is a negative selection portfolio
you end up
with 50 to 100 positions
in stocks
or the assets that you trade
which you don't even want
the reason why you're doing it
is to bring business
into the firm
so you get the commission
so the bank gets the commission
and where do those commissions
get tagged?
they get tagged
on the sales desk
so the traders
on the trading desk
offer the bank's balance sheet
to the world
as liquidity
and then pension funds
and hedge funds
come in
and use that balance sheet
to trade
and then they get rewarded
by doing big trades
on risk
by getting
nice
juicy
free agency orders
to say thank you
next week
thank you for the week before
for going on risk to me
in a situation
where you knew
you were probably going to lose money
and the ability
of the market maker
is really
priced on
their ability
to keep the commission
and we call that
a loss ratio
or a retention ratio
so if a hundred million dollars
comes in
in one year
and you manage to keep
eighty million dollars of it
which is a bloody good performance
your retention ratio
is eighty percent
which means you're a
shit hot market maker
so
that's eighty percent
of the time
eighty percent
agency
twenty percent risk
but
it's ninety percent
of the time
so only ten percent
of it
is spent
actually
doing what's called
well the polar opposite
trading
proprietarily
as in
everything that the bank does
proprietary to doing business
with clients
that's why it's called
proprietary trading
and it's the polar opposite
because the traders
are using the bank's
balance sheet
to do the opposite
of a negative selection
portfolio
so what they're trying to do
is use the bank's
balance sheet
to make back
the twenty million dollars
that they lost
doing business
so the vast majority
of the time is spent
supervising
algorithms
ten percent
spent managing a positive
selection portfolio
and they're typically
long short portfolios
so they want to be
longer stock
they want to be
shorter stock
they build that
portfolio
and they run it
and typically
it's a one to three
month
time horizon
and this is what a typical
guy's business
so if you just walk up to a
guy on a trading desk
at an investment bank
and say
what do you trade
you guys say
I'll trade
the top
S&P 500 stocks
for XYZ bank
this is what the business
will probably look like
in a typical fiscal year
commission generated
50 million
with a retention ratio
of 70%
and then the same amount
of commission coming in
roughly speaking
exposure
in the proprietary trading
account
trying to make
20%
and then
the net
loss ratio
so you end up
with a total revenue
of 45
on a turnover
of 50
which is a pretty
good performance
that's a decent year
the bank then
gives that trader
a discretionary bonus
so they just
pull a number
out of thin air
it's not fixed
it's just made up
so when you sign
your contract
to go and work
for an investment bank
your contract
literally says
your bonus is
at the discretion
of the bank
and you have
your bonus meetings
leading into
the day you'll get told
and then you get
called in and get told
and that's the
the day that
everybody in the year
looks forward to
or dreads
basic salary is paid
which is
usually less than
your bonus
if you're getting
paid a bonus
less than your
basic salary
you shouldn't be
working in the
investment banking
industry
and then an overhead
cost
because it cost the
bank a million dollars
for you to sit there
so total profit
attributed to a trader
might look something
like that
these days
in my day
it was double
so really what have we
learned here
well
in emulating
professional traders
at an investment bank
you're not really
trying to emulate
at all
what the professional trader
does as a market maker
your objective
as a retail trader
to make money
with your own money
is more aligned
with their
positive selection
portfolio
so 90%
of everything
they do
has got nothing
to do with your
interest
unless you want
to go and do
unless you want to go
and work for a bank
and become one of the
guys that supervises
electronic orders
but most importantly
or one of the most
important things
you'll see that a trader
in an investment bank
has a basic salary
I'll make a statement
and never ever
ever forget it
every single
professional trader
in the world
has a basic salary
every professional trader
if they don't
they're being
legged over
by the company
that's hired them
and if they make
no money
in the proprietary
trading account
they don't get a bonus
if they make money
they get a bonus
we'll come back
to this later
the issue
of a basic salary
so what does
a professional trader
at a hedge fund do
first things first
protect the capital
of their investors
by making money
in markets
that go up
and markets
that go down
but professional traders
at hedge funds
usually called
PMs
portfolio managers
why?
pretty obvious
they manage portfolios
they don't go home
at night
with no positions
walk in the next day
get massively long
the market
and then close out
at 3 in the afternoon
and go for drinks
they're running portfolios
they take overnight risk
and the time horizon
can be anything
from 1 to 18 months
usually
but it's usually 3
a 3 month time horizon
there's no market
making activity
but their function
is extremely similar
to the prop trading
function
at an investment bank
the positive selection
portfolio
the only difference
is the structure
of the business
that they operate in
essentially
the trading
the way they do things
the processes
they go through
to choose
what they want
to buy in short
are exactly the same
it's no coincidence
why there's so many
of the world's
top hedge fund managers
are ex
Goldman Sachs
ex
Morgan Stanley
they've all been
prop traders
at investment banks
in the past
and then they've gone on
to do the same function
with outside investors money
not the bank's money
the guys at investment banks
are utilising
the bank's capital
so essentially
that's shareholders money
they're public companies
so let's go through
some basics
of a hedge fund
but why is it called
a hedge fund
because they use strategies
that hedge up risk
so they can make money
when the market
goes up and down
but how is it structured
it's just an investment vehicle
for high net worth
and institutions
to invest in
and you have an onshore
management company
and an offshore
holding company
and the management company
charges
a 1-2% management fee
to manage the money
and an annual performance fee
on the money they make
using the capital
in their positive selection portfolio
but what's very interesting
about hedge funds
is that when they go
and pitch high net worth
in institutions
as part of their pitch
and one of the conditions
that investors have
to invest in the fund
is that
in a given year
on the performance fee
at least half
of the performance fee
must be reinvested
in the fund
no hedge fund
charges a performance fee
takes their money
and runs
they have to reinvest
at least half of it
so let's have a look
at a typical hedge fund structure
hedge fund example
of what might happen
in a typical year
so let's say
they're holding
a hundred million dollars
of investor money
as assets under management
and they've got 50 positions
25 long
25 short
and they have a self-imposed
position limit
so no position
can be bigger
than 2%
in the portfolio
so nothing
can be over
2 million dollars
that's a very
diverse hedge fund
they're not taking
a great deal
of risk
let's say
last year
they made
a 20% return
on a portfolio
with mid-teens
volatility
that's a good
hedge fund
if they're diverse
that much
they make 20%
and they get
and it's on
mid-teens
volatility
they're doing
really well
they've had
a good year
they charge
a 2%
management fee
based on the
AUM
at the beginning
of the year
so the
onshore
management company
takes 2 million
dollars of fees
and 4 million
performance
in that situation
but 2 million
of that 4 million
is reinvested
so what happens
it's pretty obvious
they don't get paid
a performance fee
if they lose money
they get the
management fee
so first of all
what does the
management fee
actually do
what's it for
anyone take a guess
exactly
the onshore
management fee
goes to pay
for all of the
infrastructure
of the fund
including
basic salaries
of everybody
in the office
that's the first
thing
all professional
traders have
a basic salary
and so do
hedge fund managers
but what about
the performance
when they have
a bad year
they don't get
paid
in a good year
what do they do
they reinvest
their money
into the fund
so the fund
grows
so what do
retail traders
have to do
if they're trying
to emulate
successful hedge fund
managers
reinvest their money
so when they
make money
they take
more risk
when they
lose money
they don't
increase their
exposure
it's pretty
obvious
no
so why do
retail traders
do the total
opposite
secure their
profits
yeah
so they're
taking their
money out
of their
trading
account
that's a
typical
behaviour
yeah
the holy
grail for a
hedge fund
manager
is to grow
the fund
let's say
from 100
million in
year one
to 5
billion
in year
six
and a
standard
industry
metric
is applied
to sell
the hedge
fund
there'll be
a value
to the
funds
because
they've
got
five
billion
of assets
under
management
does anybody
know what
it is
the standard
industry
metric
for asset
managers
and hedge
funds
it's
one tenth
of assets
under
management
so they'll
sell that
fund
for 500
million
and they'll
have their
own money
in the
fund
the whole
time
and be
increasing
their
holding
the whole
time
so they
grow that
from 100
to 5
billion
and walk
away
with 500
million
that's a
successful
hedge fund
manager
so you
should really
be taking
a few
messages
from this
if your
objective
here is
to make
money
which it
is
no one
goes into
the market
to lose
money
we all
go in
with the
idea
that we're
going to
become
superstars
and make
loads of
money
so the
objective
here is
to make
money
using
our
own
money
so out
of this
retail
traders
should take
several
really
important
messages
hedge fund
managers
use their
own
money
unaccept
outside
investor
money
investment
bank
traders
don't
so what
does that
mean
for a
retail
trader
your
objective
is a
hell of
a lot
more
aligned
with
that
of a
hedge fund
manager
the
prop
function
and
hedge fund
managers
they both
hold
long
short
diverse
portfolios
with a
fairly
medium
term
to
long
term
time
horizon
obviously
depending
on what
company
you work
for
and what
the
investment
mandate
is
they both
get paid
a basic
salary
that's really
important
so many
retail traders
think
trading is for
income
it isn't
people must
have seen it
before where
you get the
message
emails
you can make
$10,000 a month
trading the
international forex
markets
so people do it
they open a
trading account
100 grand
in month
in month one
they make
10 grand
they take
out the
10 grand
they spend
it
in month
two
they lose
10 grand
then they
take 10 grand
out
and they're
left with
and they
spend
10 grand
so what
are they
doing
when they
make money
they're taking
money out of
their trading
account
when they
lose money
they're taking
more risk
they're doing
the total
opposite to
what professional
traders do
you should
never ever
ever as a
retail trader
take an
income
from your
trading
account
it's not
an income
strategy
if you want
an income
strategy
buy a bunch
of stocks
and hold
them for a
decade
that pay
a 4%
dividend
yield
go and buy
a flat
and rent
it out
to somebody
that'll pay
you an income
go and buy
a government
bond
that'll pay
you a coupon
trading is
not for
income
every professional
trader knows
that
that's why
they charge
a management
fee
so they
can get
paid a
basic
salary
and the
industry
is very
very competitive
it's so
competitive
in the
hedge fund
industry
people going
and pitching
high net worth
in institutions
for a limited
amount of
capital
it's so
competitive
that all of
them still
ask for a
management fee
so why do we
think they do
that because
they know that
trading is not
for income
their objective
is to grow
their account
to as big
as possible
so they can
sell the fund
so they
don't want to
take any
money out
of the
fund
they want
to reinvest
it as much
as they can
because they
want an exit
for as big
as possible
as quickly
does that
make sense
so hedge fund
managers are
literally doing
the total
opposite
to what most
retail traders
do
when they
make money
reinvest
lose money
don't increase
your risk
so let's go
through some
of the main
differences
we have touched
on some of them
already
differences between
professional traders
and retail traders
so if you're
going to compare
yourself
or try to
emulate
the best
and most
successful
professional traders
you've got to
emulate their
strategies
and from a very
basic level
we've been through
some of them
you've got to
have a basic
salary doing
something else
to begin with
otherwise you're
just not going
to grow your
account
because you'll
be forced
to take an
income from
your trading
account
and it'll
be terminal
you'll just
go to zero
either very
quickly
or slowly
but you will
be at zero
at some point
if you do
that
and the
principle
of taking
more risk
when you
make money
and taking
less risk
when you
lose money
from the
ground up
that's pretty
basic stuff
but millions
of people get
it wrong
every year
and it's
repeat and
rinse
every year
same approach
go to zero
start again
put ten grand
in your trading
account
lose it
go to zero
six months
later
start again
with another
ten grand
do it again
no one ever
learns
but the
problem is
is due to
all the
misinformation
and conflict
of interest
that exists
in the
industry
this is why
people behave
like that
so we've
touched on
one of them
already
which is
pretty obvious
what a
professional
trader actually
does
you'll get
tons of
people in
the industry
who have
got the
conflict of
interest
showing you
or trying to
convince you
that professional
traders approach
the markets
in a particular
way
when they
actually don't
and that
person who's
telling you
that has
never been
a professional
trader
so how
would they
know
there's a
lot of
misinformation
and the
is due
to a
conflict
of
interest
so what
is the
difference
what are
the approach
differences
so hedge fund
manager
investment bank
professional
trader
with a
positive
selection
portfolio
long short
one to
three months
retail
trader
the approach
is typically
directional
day trading
around
binary
situations
what's the
approach
to risk
diversity
and risk
management
the job
of the
hedge fund
manager
and even
the guy
at the
investment
bank
in the
prop trading
function
their job
first and
foremost
is to
protect
that money
and then
seek to
grow it
so by
first
protecting
it
what's
required
real
diversity
and
proper
risk
management
all you'll
hear
talked about
on a
desk
at an
investment
bank
or a
hedge fund
is the
risk
what's the
risk here
are you on
top of
your risk
what can
we make
or lose
in one
day
with the
retail
trader
risk is
extremely
concentrated
so
when a
professional
trader looks
at a
retail
trader's
trading
book
they can't
understand
why somebody
would only
have two
or three
or four
positions
it's lunacy
they look at
it and they
just can't
understand why
so someone
might be
long the
S&P 500
might have
a long
euro
US dollar
position
and short
a dollar
yen position
but also
you've got
no diversity
you're just
going to be
up or down
on the day
and your book
is out of
control
you can't
what's going
to happen
so professional
traders will
just never
ever do
that
what's the
approach to
return
professional
traders are
seeking long
term consistent
returns
we know that
because the
objective is of
the hedge fund
managers to
get AUM
assets under
management
no one's going
to invest in
the hedge fund
or that
trader
if they're up
10% one
month
down 10%
the next
month
and they
just never
make money
you want
consistent
returns
smoothed
over time
which show
a strong
track record
and
behaviour
in good
times and
bad times
in the
portfolio
where people
recognise you
do the right
thing in
good and
bad times
so you
show good
behaviour in
your track
record
so when
you make
money
you know
you're making
money and
you increase
your risk
and when
you lose
money you
do the
right things
to reduce
risk
and if you
show that
over a
number of
years with
smooth returns
you're going to
have a much
easier job
pitching somebody
for 100
million to
invest in
your hedge fund
than if you're
just all over
the place
retail trader
polar opposite
a good month
up massively
a bad month
loses all
their money
or half the
money
what's the
outcome
for the
professional
trader
it's all
about capital
preservation
and growth
sell the
fund
or get
higher fees
or bigger
bonuses
2% on
5 billion
is a lot
of money
what's the
outcome for a
retail trader
just capital
destruction
assets go to
zero
try again
next year
professional
trader
what's the
approach to
income
ensure your
minimum standard
of living
by making
sure you have
a basic
salary
retail trader
working full
or part time
in a normal
day job
but they
trade for
extra income
which means
if you open
your account
with $100,000
even if you're
good
in 10 years
time
you'll still
have $100,000
because you're
taking a salary
in terms of growth
professional traders
will add
when winning
and reduce
risk when
losing
what happens
to the retail
trader
take income
when winning
and seek risk
when losing
so taking
more risk
what's the
result
hedge fund
managers will
grow their
assets under
management
retail trader
trading account
goes to zero
outcome
the same as
before
so here's the
differences
on one page
expectations
management
all professional
traders aim
to get rich
slowly
compound returns
all professional
traders
seek
consistent
smoothed
risk adjusted
returns
compounded
so let's do
a bit of
compound math
if you open
a trading
account
with 10,000
pounds
in year
one
and you
use that
10,000
pounds
to enable
you to
take
40,000
pounds
worth of
exposure
if you
get a
25%
return
each year
so call
it 2%
a month
on average
smoothed
over time
there will
be months
where you
lose
but if you
make an
average of
2%
a month
in what
year does
your account
become a
million
anyone know
has anyone
ever done it
in a spreadsheet
worked it
out
the 8th
wonder of
the world
compounding
Einstein did
actually call it
the 8th wonder
of the world
it's about
2 thirds of
the way
through year
so you
can grow
10,000
pounds
at 2%
a month
on average
to over
a million
by the
end of
year 7
if you
just keep
reinvesting
and never
taking an
income
but one
thing is
guaranteed
if you
take an
income
of 2,000
pounds
a month
you'll
still be
at
or you'll
be at
zero
so you've
got two
choices
you either
do it
that way
the
professional
trade away
the real
way
or you
do it
the retail
trade away
and just
never ever
ever become
wealthier
I don't
think we
need to go
over this
well again
no income
from trading
retail
traders
want to
take income
professional
traders
don't
they ensure
their basic
salaries
so they
make sure
they get
their minimum
living standards
from making
a basic
salary
so to
recap
and we
know what
the
differences
are
the majority
of retail
traders
just lose
money
because they
do the
opposite
of what
all
successful
professional
traders
do
in all
ways
approach
risk
income
everything
everything's
the opposite
okay so
welcome back
that was
professional
traders and
retail traders
and I guess
what have we
learnt here
well I think
what we've
learnt here
in terms of
what professional
traders actually
are
is that there
is a very
big
misguided
perception
or misinterpretation
of what professional
traders are
and what they
actually do
I think in the
retail trading
community
we need to
clarify quite a
few things
in terms of
the professional
traders objectives
because essentially
as retail traders
you're trading
with your own
money and you're
trying to emulate
the successful
professional traders
and trying to
make money
with your own
money
well it seems
that we can
forget about
guys at
investment banks
the only thing
to take away
from guys at
investment banks
is that they
have a basic
salary
the rest of
the stuff they
do it's just
not in the
same objective
as the retail
trader
investment banks
are trading
with the bank's
money
when they're
doing proprietary
trading
as in
all business
within the bank
that's proprietary
to doing business
with clients
the vast majority
of the time
and we're talking
80-90% of the
time
of a professional
trader at an
investment bank
they are trading
with clients
so either on
behalf of the
client
or
they're trading
on the other
side of the
client
and taking
risk
using the
bank's money
on the other
side
nothing a retail
trader does
is in any
way similar
so these
guys in
terms of
80-90%
of their
day-to-day
activities
retail traders
you just don't
need to think
about it
the only thing
that they do
which is similar
is proprietary
trading
which is using
the bank's
money to make
back the losses
from doing
client business
in their
approach
in terms of
prop trading
that's what
we're interested
in because that
approach is very
similar to hedge
fund managers
it's no coincidence
that most hedge
fund managers
originally start
off at
investment banks
the proprietary
trading function
of a guy in
investment bank
is very similar
to the approach
of a hedge fund
manager
but remember
one thing
the guy in the
investment bank
80-90% of what
they do is
irrelevant for
retail traders
and the second
thing they get
a basic salary
hedge fund managers
different
in that
they have their
own money
in the fund
very similar
to retail traders
in their objectives
because a hedge fund
manager wants to
create wealth
but doing it
in a very different
way
a very different
way to the way
retail traders
would expect
firstly
they're charging
a management fee
so they put
their own money
in their fund
and they accept
outside investors
money
and they charge
a management fee
some would say
the reason why
they accept
outside investors
money is so
they can charge
a management fee
so they can get
a basic salary
the management fee
pays for all
of the infrastructure
and basic salaries
of the office
and the people
at the hedge fund
typically
a basic salary
management fee
would be
1-2%
on assets
under management
AUM
and then
on top of that
they're charging
a performance fee
typically
would be 20%
of any money
made for outside investors
so what have we got here
we've got a basic salary
which protects
the downside wealth
of the hedge fund manager
it protects their downside
so it protects
the hedge fund manager
from becoming poorer
what have we got
on the upside
we've got the performance fee
where the hedge fund manager
charges the performance fee
typically 20%
to become wealthier
now
how do they actually
become wealthier
well what they do is
they have contracts
with their outside investors
and typically
their outside investors
will make
the manager
contract
to
putting at least
half the management fee
back
half the performance fee
apologies
back into
the hedge fund
the strategy
so what does that mean
well
let's go through
an example
where
a hedge fund manager
charges
2%
management fee
and 20%
performance fee
and
let's say
for example
it's your money
well
if you put in
and it becomes
in one year
so let's say
that's 100 million US dollars
and the hedge fund manager
makes
20 million dollars
in one year
well
if the hedge fund manager
came to you
and said
I'm going to charge you
a 20% performance fee
4 million dollars
and I'm going to take
all of that money
and just not reinvest
in the fund
well
you're not going to be
very happy
you're not going to be happy
because it gives you
the message
that the hedge fund manager
is not willing to invest
in their own strategy
that defeats
the whole purpose
the whole purpose here
is that
everybody
becomes wealthier
together
and that
the hedge fund manager's
winning strategy
is so good
that
outside investors
want to invest in it
therefore
if it's so good
why is the person
not investing
in their own strategy
well it doesn't make
any sense
so typically
what will happen is
they'll be contracted
to invest
at least half
of the performance fee
back into the fund
so out of that
4 million dollars
2 million dollars
will be reinvested
now what happens
if the hedge fund manager
doesn't make money
so the 100 million
stays at 100 million
well it's pretty obvious
there's no performance fee
therefore there's no
reinvestment
of the performance fee
so what do hedge fund managers do
they invest in themselves
and increase
their trading accounts
because a hedge fund
essentially
if you look at it
in that way
it is a trading account
they invest
in
themselves
when they're making money
and they don't invest
when they're not making money
and the objective
is
obviously
to make money
every year
but every year
if they're making money
to increase
their assets
under management
what does this mean
for retail traders
simple
you don't take income
from your trading account
you grow your trading account
over your lifetime
until retirement
now
think of the opposite situation
where if you're a retail trader
and this is a very typical situation
in the retail trading community
the vast majority of retail traders
are under the impression
that trading
is
for some reason
for income
whether it's
they're going to do it full time
or
what most people do
is they try to trade
and they try to
supplement
their salary
by taking a monthly income
from their trading account
so let's think of this
in round numbers again
let's say
you put $100,000
in your trading account
and
you
have the
impression
that
you're going to make
$10,000 a month
trading the forex markets
and
you're going to take out
$10,000 a month
in income
to supplement
your
salary
doing something else
so
you open your account
and
after month one
you're up
$10,000
what's the next thing you do?
well
you need to pay yourself
$10,000
so you take
out of your account
what happens
your capital is back
to $100,000
now if you go and spend
that $10,000
you're no wealthier
so there's no point
now
what happens
if
you then in month two
lose $10,000
but
you're relying on your trading account
to pay you a salary
of $10,000
well that just means
you're going to take
$10,000
out of your account
you're going to go
from $100,000
to $80,000
now to maintain
the same
levels of exposure
you're going to have
to take
more risk
to get
the same return
that you had
previously
so
all that you're doing
is the opposite
of what a professional
trader does
a professional trader
doesn't take money
out when they're winning
and doesn't put money in
when they're losing
but they don't take
more risk either
so
what you're actually doing
is the opposite
when you make $10,000
you're taking it out
as income
and
when
you lose
you're taking income again
which means
you're taking more risk
to maintain
the same levels
of exposure
now
if you're going to invest
in a hedge fund
I'd bet
if you were going to put
your life savings
in a hedge fund
you would
want to see
consistency
of returns
you would want to see
diversity
in risk management
you would want to see
responsibility
and
the consistency
that they get
comes
over a long
period of time
now if you put
your money in that fund
what's probably
the most important thing
out of everything
probably the most
important thing
is that the manager
themselves invests
when they're winning
when they're actually
making money
they don't take it
out of the fund
they put it back
in the fund
that's not going to
sit with you
very well
if the hedge fund manager
charges you a performance fee
and takes their money out
it just means you're sponsoring
the hedge fund manager
to become wealthier
but they're not investing
in their own strategy
to become even more wealthier
so it doesn't make any sense
it defeats the whole purpose
so
a couple of things here
first
basic salaries
don't be under the impression
that
you're going to
for some reason
leave your job
you're going to
trade
with your own money
and you're going to take
a salary from your trading account
because the only thing
that's going to happen
if
on a monthly basis
you take
money out
when you're winning
and you take more risk
when you're losing
the only thing
that can happen
over time
is that your trading account
goes to zero
secondly
the approach
has to be
one of consistency
diversity of risk management
and reinvestment
of your money
when you're winning
and taking no
further risk
when you're losing
or not making money
now this situation
of going to zero
let's discuss this
a little bit further
what happens
if
you're in this situation
where
every time
you make money
you take money
out of your trading account
and every time
you lose money
you take more risk
well
you're going to zero
over time
it just depends how long
what happens
if you leverage
this situation
so
we now
borrow
a million dollars
to reinvest
in the same strategy
but we use
the hundred thousand dollars
as collateral
to borrow
the one million dollars
to invest
in this strategy
well
it just means
your hundred thousand dollars
used as collateral
to cover losses
against the million dollars
is going to go
to zero quicker
because you're going
to have to pay
those liabilities
and this is what happens
in every trading account
that we call
a margin account
margin
is just money
that's deposited
in your trading account
and it's used
as collateral
to enable you
to borrow
through the brokerage
company
ten times
typically
in stocks
and indices
and a hundred times
in forex
and if you do that
all that's going
to happen
if you leverage
this strategy
is you're going
to go to zero
quicker
it's the only thing
that can happen
you take money out
when you're winning
you take more risk
when you're losing
the outcome
is terminal
your account
tends
towards zero
and goes
quicker
so you just
shouldn't do it
and you'll end up
getting what we call
a margin call
where the broker
literally gives you
a call
a telephone call
and sends you an email
and says you have to
put more money
in your trading account
to cover the losses
in your account
if you don't do that
you're wiped out
so let's go
let's summarize here
before we move on
if you're going to
use your own money
to trade
be under no illusion
professional traders
all have basic salaries
you should have a basic
salary as well
you should maintain
this basic salary
you should trade
to begin with
as a hobby
when you get good
at trading
at some point
in the future
it may become
a viable option
that it becomes
a profession
but as it stands
if you're working
you've got a basic salary
and you're not
a professional trader
you're a retail trader
maintain your basic salary
and protect your downside
wealth
that's the first thing
secondly
your account
your capital
do not take income
from your trading account
when you're winning
do not take more risk
when you're losing
you should view
your trading account
as an asset
in itself
and the asset
you're aiming
to increase
the value
of this asset
over your lifetime
between now
and retirement
or even the day
you die
that asset
sits on your balance sheet
as a human being
and the value
of that asset
is completely linked
to your ability
as a trader
so if you're good
you increase
the value
of your account
and you have an option
to put more money
into your trading account
and keep increasing
the size of your account
if you're bad
you don't
reinvest
in that strategy
you just
try to get better
and when you get better
then you have the option
to invest more money
it's very straightforward
but many many people
make the mistake
because of misinformation
in the market
and in a big bad world
that
professional traders
take income
from their trading account
professional traders
have concentrated risk
they take big risks
they're running around
screaming at lots of people
they've got hundreds
of computer screens
it just doesn't work
like that at all
in fact
most of the things
that you probably think
a professional trader does
they're probably
the total opposite
of what you would expect
in reality
and in reality
from a professional trader's
perspective
I can tell you
they absolutely are
the opposite
of what you would expect
so
just take those things
on board
make sure you know them
now that you know
what a professional trader does
you can move on
to understanding
what successful
professional traders do
as in
the guys who have got
the same objectives
as us
the hedge fund managers
that trade
with their own money
trying to become wealthier
using their own money
as capital
that's what we're going
to move on to now
in video number two
I'll see you in clip two
Voo
sounds in favor
very sweet
in
you
means
they're estadounid
I'm
them
you
I
whom